<section id="actionbar" role="wrapper">
	<title>Introduction to the toolbar
	<section id="actionbar_actionbar">
		<title>What is the toolbar (action bar)?
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Action Bar
			</primary>
			<see>Toolbar</see>
		</indexterm>
		<indexterm>
			<primary>Toolbar
			</primary>
		</indexterm>
		
			The
			_toolbar bar_
			(formerly known as action bar) is represented as of Android 5.0 via the
			`Toolbar`
			view group and can be placed into your layout file.
			It can
			display the
			activity
			title,
			icon, actions which
			can be
			triggered, additional
			views
			and
			other
			interactive
			items. It can also be used for navigation in your
			application.
		
		
			Before Android 5.0 the location of the toolbar (actionbar) was hard code to the
			top
			of
			the
			activity.
		
		
			The toolbar  is enabled for devices which specify a target SDK
			of API version 11 or higher. It is possible to
			disable the toolbar
			via
			the used theme, but the default Android themes have it enabled.
		

		
			Applications with a target SDK version less than API 11 use the
			_options menu_
			if such a button is present on the device. The option menu is
			displayed if
			the user presses the
			_Option_
			button. The
			toolbar bar
			is superior to the options menu, as the action
			bar
			is
			clearly visible, while the
			options menu
			is only
			shown on request.
			In
			case of the options menu,
			the user may not recognize that options
			are
			available in the application.
		

	</section>
	<section id="actionbar_example">
		<title>Example

		
			The following screenshot shows the
			toolbar
			of the Google+
			Android application with interactive items and a
			navigation bar. On
			top it also indicates that the user can open a navigation bar on
			the side of the application.
		

		
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/actionbar_google10.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<textobject>
					<phrase>ActionBar Screenshot</phrase>
				</textobject>
			</mediaobject>
		
	</section>
	<section id="actionbar_libraries1">
		<title>Action bar on devices lower than API 21
		
			The
			toolbar
			has been introduced in Android 5.0 (API 21). If you want to use
			the toolbar
			on devices with an earlier
			Android
			release you can use the downport provided by the
			`appcompat-v7`
			support library. Add for this the latest
			version of
			`com.android.support:appcompat`
			to your Gradle build file, for example, at this point
			`com.android.support:appcompat-v7:22.2.0`
			.
			See the following link for setting up the library v7
			in your project:
			<ulink url="http://developer.android.com/tools/support-library/setup.html">Setting up the support library</ulink>
			.
		
		This section focuses on the description of using the toolbar
			bar without the support library. You
			can
			port
			your application to an lower API version using the support library. 
		

	</section>
</section>