<section id="androidsecurity" role="wrapper">
	<title>Security and permissions</title>
	<section id="androidsecurity_general">
		<title>Security concept in Android</title>
		<para>
			The Android system installs every Android application with a
			unique user and group ID. Each
			application file is
			private to this
			generated user, e.g., other
			applications cannot access these files. In
			addition, each Android
			application is started in its own
			process.
		</para>
		<para>
			Therefore, by means of the underlying Linux kernel,
			every Android
			application is
			isolated from other
			running
			applications.
		</para>
		<para>
			If data should be shared, the application must do this
			explicitly via an Android component which handles the
			sharing of the
			data,
			e.g.,
			via a service
			or a content provider.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="androidsecurity_permissions">
		<title>Permission concept in Android</title>
		<para>Android contains a permission system and predefined
			permissions
			for certain tasks. Every application can request
			required
			permissions
			and also define new permissions. For example, an application may
			declare
			that it
			requires access to
			the Internet.
		</para>
		<para> Permissions have different levels. Some permissions are
			automatically granted by the Android system, some are
			automatically
			rejected. In most cases the requested permissions are presented
			to
			the
			user before installing the
			application. The user needs
			to
			decide if
			these permissions shall be given to the application.
		</para>


		<para>
			If the user denies a required permission, the related
			application cannot be
			installed. The check of
			the permission
			is only
			performed during
			installation, permissions
			cannot be denied or granted
			after the
			installation.
		</para>

		<para>
			An Android application declares the required permissions in its
			<filename>AndroidManifest.xml</filename>
			configuration file. It can also define additional permissions which
			it can use to restrict access to certain
			components.
		</para>
		<note>
			<para>
				Not all users pay attention to the required permissions
				during
				installation. But some
				users do and they write
				negative reviews
				on
				Google Play if they believe the application is too invasive.
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>

	<section id="androidsecurity_runtime_permissions">
		<title>Runtime permissions</title>
		<para>
			Android 6.0 Marshmallow (API 23) introduced a new runtime permission model. If your application targets Android 6.0,
			you must use the new permissions model. See
			<ulink url="https://developer.android.com/preview/features/runtime-permissions.html">Official documentation</ulink>
			for details.
		</para>
	</section>

</section>