<section id="resourcequalifiers_translations1" role="wrapper">
	<title>Strings and translations</title>

	<section id="resourcequalifiers_translationsqualifier">
		<title>Strings and translations</title>
		<para>
			You can also use resource selectors for your
			<filename class="directory">values</filename>
			folder with contains, for example, your string values. Use the
			<filename class="directory">values-qualifier</filename>
			folder for this.
		</para>
		<para>
			For
			example, to provide English and German text resources, use
			the
			<filename class="directory">values-en</filename>
			and
			<filename class="directory">values-de</filename>
			folder.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="resourcequalifiers_plurals">
		<title>Plurals</title>
		<para>
			Android supports Plurals. Plurals are XML based resources which
			allow
			to handle different quantities. This way you can select the
			right text
			based on the quantity. In your XML file you specify values
			for the
			quantities “zero”, “one”, “two”, “many”, “few”, “many”,
			“other” and in
			your code you use the
			<code>getQuantityString()</code>
			method to
			get the correct value. You can also format strings. If now
			Strings
			are formated then you pass in the plural resources and the
			number. If
			Objects should be used for formating you pass them as
			additional
			parameters.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="java">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/plurals/string.xml" />
			</programlisting>
		</para>
		<para>For example the following will define a plural. This file needs
			to be in the “res/values” directory and in this example it is called
			“plurals”.
		</para>
		<para>
			<programlisting language="java">
				<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
					parse="text" href="./examples/plurals/Test.java" />
			</programlisting>
		</para>


		<para>Note that the selection is
			made based on grammatical necessity. A
			string for zero in English
			will be ignored even if the quantity is 0,
			because 0 isn’t
			grammatically different from 2, or any other number
			except 1 (“no
			tutorial”, “one tutorial”, “two tutorials”, and so on).
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="resourcequalifiers_translations_translations">
		<title>Using Google translate</title>
		<para>You can either translate your String manually (either yourself
			or a paid organization) or use a machine translation.
		</para>
		<para>
			White a machine based translation is not optional it might be a
			good
			starting point or the only option if the budget for the
			application is
			limited.
			<ulink url="http://translate.google.com/toolkit">Google Translate</ulink>
			provides free machine translation with the option to hire
			professionals for checks.
		</para>
		<tip>
			<para>The tool offer free suggestions but it first offers you (at the
				moment) a paid translation. Click through this to get to the machine
				translation.
			</para>
		</tip>
	</section>
</section>